<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A proclamation concerning a cessation of arms. Agreed and concluded on at Siggings-town, in the county of Kildare, the fifteenth day of September, in the nineteenth yeer of His Majesties raign, by and between James Marquesse of Ormonde, Lieutenant Generall of His Majesties army in the Kingdom of Ireland, for and in the name our gracious Soveraign Lord Charles, by the grace of God, King of Great Britain, France, and Ireland, &amp;c. By vertue of His Majesties Commission bearing date at Dublin the last of August, in the said nineteenth year of His Majesties Raign, of the one party. And Donogh Viscount Muskerry, Sir Lucas Dillon Knight; Nicholas Plunket Esquire; Sir Robert Talbot Baronet; Sir Richard Barnwell Baronet; Torlogh O Neale, Geoffrey Brown, Ever Mac-Gennis and John Walsh, Esquires; authorized by His Majesties Roman Catholique subjects, ... To treat and conclude with the said marquesse for a cessation of arms, by vertue of an authority given unto them, bearing date at Cashel, the seventh day of September, in the said nineteenth yeer of His Majesties raign, of the other party. Whereunto is added, an instrument touching the manner of payment of 30800 pounds sterling by severall payments. Ordered by the Commons in Parliament, that this proclamation be forthwith printed: H: Elsynge, Cler. Parl. D. Com.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1643</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 34 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 7 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A87323</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing I605</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E71_29</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R32216</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99872315</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99872315</idno>
            <idno type="VID">124745</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A87323)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 124745)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 12:E71[29])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A proclamation concerning a cessation of arms. Agreed and concluded on at Siggings-town, in the county of Kildare, the fifteenth day of September, in the nineteenth yeer of His Majesties raign, by and between James Marquesse of Ormonde, Lieutenant Generall of His Majesties army in the Kingdom of Ireland, for and in the name our gracious Soveraign Lord Charles, by the grace of God, King of Great Britain, France, and Ireland, &amp;c. By vertue of His Majesties Commission bearing date at Dublin the last of August, in the said nineteenth year of His Majesties Raign, of the one party. And Donogh Viscount Muskerry, Sir Lucas Dillon Knight; Nicholas Plunket Esquire; Sir Robert Talbot Baronet; Sir Richard Barnwell Baronet; Torlogh O Neale, Geoffrey Brown, Ever Mac-Gennis and John Walsh, Esquires; authorized by His Majesties Roman Catholique subjects, ... To treat and conclude with the said marquesse for a cessation of arms, by vertue of an authority given unto them, bearing date at Cashel, the seventh day of September, in the said nineteenth yeer of His Majesties raign, of the other party. Whereunto is added, an instrument touching the manner of payment of 30800 pounds sterling by severall payments. Ordered by the Commons in Parliament, that this proclamation be forthwith printed: H: Elsynge, Cler. Parl. D. Com.</title>
                  <author>Ormonde, James Butler, Duke of, 1610-1688.</author>
                  <author>England and Wales. Parliament. House of Commons. aut</author>
                  <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1625-1649 : Charles I)</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>8, 7-10 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed first at Dublin by William Bladen, printer to the Kings Most Excellent Majesty; and now reprinted at Loudou [sic] for Edw. Husbands,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>October 21. 1643.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Place of publication from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Variant: "London" in imprint is spelled correctly.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Civil War, 1642-1649 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Ireland --  History --  Rebellion of 1641 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-12</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-01</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-11</date>
            <label>Leah Yurasek</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-11</date>
            <label>Leah Yurasek</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:124745:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>A PROCLAMATION Concerning <hi>A Ceſſation of ARMS.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Agreed and concluded on at <hi>Siggings-town,</hi> in the county of <hi>Kildare,</hi> the Fifteenth day of <hi>Septem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber,</hi> in the Nineteenth yeer of His Majeſties Raign, by and between <hi>James</hi> Marqueſſe of <hi>Ormonde,</hi> Lieutenant Generall of His Majeſties Army in the Kingdom of <hi>Ireland,</hi> for and in the name of our gracious Soveraign Lord <hi>CHARLES,</hi> by the Grace of God, King of <hi>Great Britain, France,</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> &amp;c. By vertue of His Majeſties Commiſſion bear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing date at <hi>Dublin</hi> the laſt of <hi>Auguſt,</hi> in the ſaid Nineteenth year of His Majeſties Raign, of the one party. And <hi>Donogh</hi> Viſcount <hi>Muskerry,</hi> Sir <hi>Lucas Dillon</hi> Knight; <hi>Nicholas Plun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ket</hi> Eſquire; Sir <hi>Robert Talbot</hi> Baronet; Sir <hi>Richard-Barn well</hi> Baronet; <hi>Torlogh O Neale, Geoffrey Brown, Ever Mac-Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nis</hi> and <hi>John Walſh,</hi> Eſquires; Authoriſed by His Majeſties Roman Catholique Subjects, of whoſe party they are, and now in Arms in the ſaid Kingdom, &amp;c. To Treat and Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clude with the ſaid Marqueſſe for a Ceſſation of Arms, by vertue of an Authority given unto them, bearing date at <hi>Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhel,</hi> the Seventh day of <hi>September,</hi> in the ſaid Nineteenth yeer of His Majeſties Raign, of the other party.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Whereunto is added, An Inſtrument touching the manner of pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of</hi> 30800 <hi>pounds ſterling by ſeverall Payments.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>ORdered by the Commons in Parliament, That this Proclamation be forthwith printed:</p>
            <p>
               <hi>H<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Elſynge, Cler. Parl. D. Com.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Printed firſt at <hi>Dublin</hi> by <hi>William Bladen,</hi> Printer to the Kings moſt Ex<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>cellent Majeſty; And now Reprinted at <hi>London</hi> for <hi>Edw. Husbands.</hi> October 21. 1643.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="proclamation">
            <pb n="2" facs="tcp:124745:2"/>
            <head>By the Lords Juſtices and Councell.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>Jo: BORLASE. HEN. TICHBORN.</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">V</seg>Pon conſideratio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>n had of the annexed Articles of Ceſſation of Arms, whereby it is concluded and ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>corded, That there be a Ceſſation of Arms, and of all Acts of Hoſtility, for one whole yeer, beginning the Fifteenth day of September, Anno Domini, One thouſand Six hundred Forty three, at the hour of Twelve of the clock of the ſaid day. We the Lords Iuſtices and Councell, according to His Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſties Letters of the One and thirtieth day of Iuly laſt, Do by this Proclamation in His Majeſties Name, ratifie, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firm, and Publiſh the ſame; And do require all His Majeſties Subjects, whom it may concern by Sea and by Land, to take notice thereof, and yeeld all Obedience thereunto, in all the parts thereof.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>Given at His Majeſties Caſtle of DUBLIN,</hi> 
                  <date>
                     <hi>the Nine<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teenth of September, 1643.</hi>
                  </date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>
                  <hi>R. Bolton. <hi>Canc.</hi> La. Dublin. Ormonde. Roſcomon. Edw. Brabazon. Ant. Midenſis. Cha. Lambart. Geo. Shurley. Getrard Lowther. Tho. Rotherham. Fr. Willoughby. Tho. Luca. La Ware. <hi>God ſave the King.</hi>
                  </hi>
               </signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="text">
            <p>ARticles of Ceſſation of Arms, agreed, and concluded on at <hi>Sig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gingstown,</hi> in the county of <hi>Kildare,</hi> the Fifteenth day of <hi>Sept.</hi> in the Nineteenth yeer of His Majeſties Raign, by and be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween <hi>James</hi> Marques of <hi>Ormond,</hi> Lieutenant Generall of His Majeſties Army in the kingdom of <hi>Ireland,</hi> for &amp; in the Name of our Gracious Soveraign Lord <hi>CHARLES,</hi> by the Grace of God, King of <hi>Great Britain, France,</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> &amp;c. By vertue of His Majeſties Commiſſion bearing date at <hi>Dublin,</hi> the laſt of <hi>Auguſt,</hi>
               <pb n="3" facs="tcp:124745:2"/>in the ſaid Nineteenth yeer of His Majeſties Raign, of the one part; And <hi>Donogh</hi> Viſcount <hi>Muskerry,</hi> Sir <hi>Lucas Dillon</hi> Knight, <hi>Nicholas Plunket</hi> Eſquire, Sir <hi>Robert Talbot</hi> Baronet, Sir <hi>Richard Barnwell</hi> Baronet, <hi>Torlogh O Neale, Geoffrey Brown, Ever Mac Gennis,</hi> and <hi>John Walſh</hi> Eſquires; Authoriſed by His Maj<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ſties Romane Catho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lique Subjects, of whoſe party they are, and now in Arms in the ſaid Kingdom, &amp;c. to Treat and Conclude with the ſaid Marqueſſe for a Ceſſation of Arms, by vertue of an Authority given unto them, bear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing date at <hi>Caſhell</hi> the Seventh day of <hi>September,</hi> in the ſaid Nine<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teenth yeer of His Majeſties Raign, of the other part.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>FIrſt,</hi> It is concluded and accorded, that there be a Ceſſation of Arms, and of all Acts of Hoſtility, between His Majeſties ſaid Romane Catholique Subjects, who are now in Arms, &amp;c. in this Kingdom, and their party, and all others His Majeſties good Subjects, for one whole yeer, to begin the Fifteenth day of <hi>September, Anno Dom.</hi> 1643. at the hour of Twelve of the clock of the ſaid day.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Item,</hi> It is concluded and accorded, That free Paſſage, Intercourſe, Commerce, and Traſſique, during the ſaid Coſſation, ſhall be between His Majeſties ſaid Romane Catholique Subjects, who are now in Arms, &amp;c. and their party, and all other His Majeſties good Subjects, and all others in League with His Majeſty by Sea and Land.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Item,</hi> It is concluded and accorded, and the ſaid Viſcount <hi>Muſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kerry,</hi> and the reſt of the above named Perſons, do promiſe and un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dertake, for and in the behalf of thoſe for whom they are Authoriſed to Treat and Conclude as aforeſaid; That all Ships, Barques, and Veſſells, which ſhall bring Proviſions to any Harbour in this King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom, in the hands or poſſeſſion of ſuch as ſhall obey the Articles of this Ceſſation, from <hi>Minehead</hi> and <hi>Whitehaven,</hi> and from all the Ports between, on that ſide where <hi>Wales</hi> is ſcituate, ſo as they be Ships be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longing to any of the ſaid Ports, and do not uſe any Acts of Hoſtility to any of the ſaid Romane Catholiques, who are now in Arms, or to any of their party, or to any who ſhall be waged, or imployed unto or by them, ſhall not be interrupted by any of their party, nor by any Ships or other Veſsells, of what Country or Nation ſoever under their power or command, or waged, imployed, or contracted with on their behalfe, or by any Forts, Garriſons, or Forces, within this King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dome under their power, in their coming to this Kingdom, or return<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing from thence.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Item.</hi> It is concluded and accorded, and the ſaid Lord Viſcount <hi>Muskery,</hi> and the reſt of the above named parties do promiſe and un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dertake
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:124745:3"/>for and in the behalfe of thoſe for whom they are authorized as aforeſaid, that all Ships, Barques, and Veſsells, which ſhall bring Proviſions to any harbour in this Kingdome, in the hands of ſuch as ſhall obey the Articles of this Ceſſation from any Ports in the kingdom of <hi>England,</hi> having his Majeſties paſſe, or the paſſe of any who is, or ſhalbe his Majeſties Admirall or Vice-admirall, or the paſſe of any Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernor or Governors of any the Ports in <hi>England,</hi> in his Majeſties hands, or which ſhall hereafter during this Ceſſation, be in His Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſties hands, or the paſſe of the ſaid Marques, ſhall not be interrupt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, by any of thoſe for whom the ſaid Lord Viſcount <hi>Muskery,</hi> and the reſt of the above named Perſons are Authorized as aforeſaid, nei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther in their coming to this Kingdome, or in their returne, ſo as they uſe not any acts of hoſtility to any of their ſaid party. And this to be a rule untill his Majeſties pleaſure be further declared therein<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> upon application of the Agents of the ſaid Roman Catholique Subjects, now in Armes, &amp;c. to his Majeſty.</p>
            <p>Item, It is concluded and accorded, and the ſaid Iames Marques of <hi>Ormond,</hi> doth promiſe and undertake, for and in the Name of His Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſty, that no interruption ſhall be given by any Ship, or Ships, under His Majeſties power and command, or waged, imployed, or contra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted with, by or in the behalfe of his Majeſty or by any of his Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſties Forts, Garriſons, or Forces, within this Kingdome, to any Ship, or Ships, that ſhall trade with any of the ſaid Roman Catholiques who are now in Arms, &amp;c or any of their party; or which ſhall come in, or go out of any the Cities, Townes, Harbours, Creeks, or Ports, of this Kingdome, in the hands of the ſaid Roman Catholiques now in Arms, &amp;c. with Arms, Ammunition, Merchandize, Commodity, or any thing whatſoever, during this Ceſſation: as on the other ſide, the ſaid <hi>Donnogh</hi> Viſcount <hi>Muskery,</hi> and the reſt above named of that party, do promiſe and undertake, for and in the behalfe of thoſe by whom they are Authorized, that no interruption ſhall be given by a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny Ship, or other Veſſell whatſoever, under the power and command of their party, or waged, imployed, or contracted with, by or in the behalfe of their party, or by any Forts, Garriſons, or Forces, within this Kingdome, in their power, to any Ship, or Ships, that ſhall trade with any of his Majeſties Subjects, obeying this Ceſſation, or which ſhall come in, or go out of any of the Cities, Townes, Harbours, or Ports of this Kingdome, which ſhall obey this Ceſſation, with Arms, Ammunition, Merchandize, Commodity, or any other thing whatſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever during this Ceſſation. Provided that no Ship, or Ships, ſhall be admitted free Trade, by colour of this Article, but ſuch as are war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ranted
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:124745:3"/>by the precedent Articles.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Item.</hi> It is concluded and accorded, that the quarters in the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vince of <hi>Leinſter</hi> be as followeth, <hi>viz.</hi> That the County of <hi>Dublin,</hi> the County of the City of <hi>Dublin,</hi> the County of the Town of <hi>Drog<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hedagh,</hi> and the County of <hi>Lowth,</hi> ſhall remaine and be during the Ceſsation, in the poſseſsion of his Majeſties Proteſtant Subjects, and of ſuch as adhere unto them reſpectively, ſaving and excepting unto the ſaid Roman Catholique Subjects, now in Armes, &amp;c. and their party, all ſuch Caſtles, Townes, Lands, Territories, and the Lands and hereditaments thereunto belonging, which upon the ſaid fifteenth day of <hi>September,</hi> 1643. at the hour aforeſaid are poſſeſſed in the ſaid counties, or any of them, by any of the ſaid party. And it is further con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cluded and accorded, that as much of the county of <hi>Meath,</hi> as in the Eaſt and South ſide of the river of <hi>Boyne,</hi> from <hi>Droghedagh</hi> to <hi>Trym,</hi> thence to the lordſhip of <hi>Moylagh,</hi> &amp; thence to <hi>Moyglare,</hi> and thence to <hi>Dublin,</hi> ſhall during the ſaid Ceſſation remain and be in the poſſeſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion of His Majeſties Proteſtant Subjects, and of ſuch as adhere unto them reſpectively, ſaving &amp; excepting to the ſaid Roman Catholique Subjects now in Armes, and their party, all ſuch Caſtles, Townes, Lands, and Territories, and the Lands, hereditaments thereunto be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longing, which upon the ſaid fifteenth day of <hi>Sept.</hi> 1643. at the hour aforeſaid are poſſeſſed by any of the ſaid Roman Catholique Subjects now in Armes, &amp;c. and of their party, within the ſaid limits, and boundaries, and that the Reſidue of the ſaid County of <hi>Meath</hi> ſhall remain in the hands and poſſeſſions of the ſaid Roman Catholique ſubjects now in armes, &amp;c. and their party, except the Caſtles, Towns, Lands, Territories, and the Lands and hereditaments thereunto be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longing, which upon the ſaid fifteenth day of <hi>Septem.</hi> 1643. at the hour aforeſaid are poſſeſſed within the ſaid laſt mentioned quarters in the County of <hi>Meath</hi> by his Majeſties Proteſtant Subjects, and ſuch as adhere unto them, or by any of them reſpectively. And that ſo much of the county of <hi>Kildare,</hi> as is on this ſide of the <hi>Liffy</hi> where <hi>Naas</hi> is ſcituate, and on the other ſide of the <hi>Liffy</hi> from <hi>Dublin</hi> weſtward into the County of <hi>Kildare,</hi> ſo far as the <hi>Rye</hi> water at <hi>Kilcock,</hi> and ſo far betwixt that and the <hi>Liffye,</hi> as ſhall be at the ſame diſtance from <hi>Dublin,</hi> as the ſaid <hi>Rye</hi> water is at <hi>Kilcock</hi> on that ſide of the <hi>Liffye;</hi> ſhall during the ſaid Ceſſation, remaine and be in the hands and poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſions of his Majeſties Proteſtant Subjects and their adherents re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpectively, except ſuch Caſtles, Townes, Territories, and the Lands and hereditaments thereunto belonging, which upon the ſaid fifteenth day of <hi>September,</hi> 1643. at the houre aforeſaid are poſſeſſed within the
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:124745:4"/>ſaid quarters by the ſaid Roman Catholique Subjects who are now in Armes, &amp;c. and their party, and that the reſidue of the ſaid County of <hi>Kildare,</hi> ſhall remaine in the hands of the ſaid Roman Catholique Subjects now in Armes, &amp;c. and their party, except ſuch Caſtles, Townes, Lands, Territories, and the Lands and Hereditaments there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>unto belonging, which upon the ſaid fifteenth day of <hi>September,</hi> 1643. at the houre aforeſaid are poſſeſſed by his Majeſties Proteſtant ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jects and their adherents reſpectively, within the ſaid laſt mentioned quarters in the ſaid County of <hi>Kildare.</hi> And that the ſeverall Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tyes of <hi>Wiglow,</hi> weſt <hi>Meath, Kings County, Queens County, Cather<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lagh, Kilkenny,</hi> County of the City of <hi>Kilkenny, Weixford,</hi> and <hi>Long<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ford,</hi> ſhall during the ſaid Ceſſation remaine in the hands of the ſaid Roman Catholique Subjects now in Armes, &amp;c. and their party, ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cept ſuch Caſtles, Townes, Lands, Territories, and the Lands and hereditaments thereunto belonging which upon the ſaid fifteenth day of <hi>September,</hi> 1643. at the houre aforeſaid, are poſſeſsed within the ſaid County, by His Majeſties Proteſtant Subjects, and their adhe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rents reſpectively.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Item,</hi> It is concluded and accorded, that what <hi>Corne,</hi> hath been ſowen by any of his Majeſties Army, or by any of his Proteſtant ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jects, or their adherents, or by any of them, within any of the quar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters alotted in the Province of <hi>Leinſter,</hi> to the ſaid other party, the ſame ſhall be enjoyed by the ſowers and manurers paying, for the ſame as they did agree, and in caſe they did not agree paying the fourth ſheafe unto ſuch Garriſon within whoſe quarters the ſame ſhall fall. And that in caſe any of the ſaid Roman Catholique Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jects, now in Armes, &amp;c. or any of their party have ſowne <hi>Corne</hi> within any the quarters alotted in the <hi>Province</hi> of <hi>Leinſter,</hi> to the ſaid other party, the ſame ſhall be enjoyed by the ſowers and ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nurers, paying for the ſame as they did agree, &amp; in caſe they did not agree paying the fourth ſheafe unto ſuch Garriſons, within whoſe quarters the ſame ſhall fall. And it is likewiſe concluded and accorded, that thoſe places which have been protected, by the Lords Iuſtices, or any Officer of His Majeſties Army, doe pay according to the agreement which was made, and if no agreement were made, to pay the fourth Sheafe, to thoſe Gariſons or perſons who prote<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted them, in whoſe ſoever quarters they are; And this to continue for a rule, other then as to ſo many of thoſe Garriſons, who granted ſuch protection, and are ſince regained by the ſaid party, or ſome of them, for whome the ſaid <hi>Dounogh</hi> Viſcount <hi>Muskery,</hi> and the perſons abovenamed are Authorized as aforeſaid. And that the Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:124745:4"/>of the Town of <hi>Baniboght</hi> in the County of <hi>Dublin,</hi> if they haue not been protected, ſhall pay according to agreement, and if no agree<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment made, then the fourth ſheafe, and to continue their poſſeſſions during this Ceſsation. And it is further concluded and accorded, that where his Majeſty, or any of his Proteſtant Subjects, or their ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>herents ſhall happen to have any Garriſon or Garriſons within the quarters ſet forth in the next precedent Article, for the ſaid other party, that ſuch Garriſon and Garriſons, ſhall have ſuch competency of the Lands aſwell profitable as unprofitable, now termed waſt, as ſhall be found neceſsary for them by any indifferent Commiſſioners, to be appointed for that purpoſe.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Item.</hi> It is concluded and accorded, that the quarters, in the Province of <hi>Munſter</hi> be as followeth, <hi>viz.</hi> That the County of the City of <hi>Corck,</hi> and ſo much of the County of <hi>Corcke,</hi> as is within the ſubſequent Garriſons, <hi>viz.</hi> From <hi>Youghall</hi> to <hi>Mogeely,</hi> thence to <hi>Formoye,</hi> thence to <hi>Michellstowne,</hi> thence to <hi>Liscarroll,</hi> and ſo in a line from <hi>Michells<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>towne,</hi> and <hi>Liſcarroll</hi> northward, as farre as His Majeſties our Gar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſons on that ſide doe entend; and from <hi>Liſcarroll,</hi> to <hi>Mallow,</hi> thence to <hi>Corcke,</hi> thence to <hi>Carrig-Croghan,</hi> thence to <hi>Rochfordstowne,</hi> thence to <hi>Bandonbridge,</hi> thence to <hi>Timmoleagie,</hi> and thence forward to the Sea, together with the ſaid Garriſons, ſhall during the ſaid Ceſſation remaine; and be in the poſſeſſion of his Majeſties Proteſtant Subjects and of ſuch as adhere unto them: Saving and excepting to the ſaid Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man Catholique Subjects now in Arms, &amp;c. and their party, all ſuch Caſtles, Townes, Lands, Territories; and the Lands and heredita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments thereunto belonging, which on the ſaid fifteenth day of <hi>Septem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber.</hi> 1643. at the houre aforeſaid are poſſeſſed in the ſaid Counties, or any of them, by any of the ſaid Roman Catholique Subjects now in Arms, &amp;c. and their party. And that the reſidue of the ſaid County of <hi>Corcke,</hi> ſhall likewiſe remaine to the ſaid party laſt named, ſaving and excepting to His Majeſties Proteſtant Subjects, and their adhe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rents, all ſuch Caſtles, Townes, Lands, Territoryes, and the Lands, and hereditaments thereunto belonging, which on the ſaid fifteenth day of <hi>September,</hi> 1643. at the houre aforeſaid, are poſſeſſed in the laſt mentioned quarters by them, or any of them. And that the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of <hi>Tipperary,</hi> the County of <hi>Limerick,</hi> the County of the City of <hi>Limericke,</hi> the County of <hi>Kerry,</hi> the County of <hi>Waterford,</hi> the County of the City of <hi>Waterford,</hi> and the County of <hi>Clare,</hi> ſhall du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring the ſaid Ceſſation remaine and be in the poſſeſſion of the ſaid Roman Catholique Subjects now in Armes, &amp;c. and their party. Except <hi>Knockmorne, Ardmore, Piltowne, Cappoquïn, Ballinetra,
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:124745:5"/>Stroncally, Lismore, Balliduffe, Lisfinny,</hi> and <hi>Tallowe,</hi> all ſcituate in the County of <hi>Waterford,</hi> or as many of them as are poſſeſſed by His MAIESTIES Proteſtant Subjects, and their adhaerents, the ſaid fifteenth day of <hi>September,</hi> 1643. at the houre aforeſaid, and likewiſe except all ſuch Caſtles, Townes, Lands, Territories, and He<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reditaments thereunto belonging, as within the ſaid Countyes reſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctively, on the ſaid fifteenth day of <hi>September</hi> 1643. at the houre a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid are poſſeſſed by any of His Majeſties Proteſtant Subjects, or ſuch as adheaere unto that party reſpectively, in the ſaid County of <hi>Waterford,</hi> and the reſt of the laſt mentioned Countyes. And it is con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cluded and accorded, that the like rule for Corne ſowen, and what ſhall be payed by places protected, and for the laying out waſts for the reſpective Garriſons, ſhalbe obſerved in the Province of <hi>Munster,</hi> as it is ſet downe for <hi>Leinster.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Item.</hi> It is concluded and accorded, that the quarters in the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vince of <hi>Vlſter,</hi> be as followeth: viz. That ſuch Countyes, Baronyes, Lands, Tenements, and hereditaments in the Province of <hi>Vlſter,</hi> which the ſaid fifteenth of <hi>September,</hi> 1643. at the hour aforeſaid, are poſſeſſed by any of his Majeſties Proteſtant Subjects, or any that adhaere unto them, and all Places protected by any Commander du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring Authority from his Majeſty, ſhall during the ſaid Ceſſation re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maine entirely in the hands and in the poſſeſſion of his Majeſties Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teſtant Subjects, and ſuch as adhaere unto them, excepting ſuch Caſtles, Lands, and hereditaments, as on the fifteenth day of <hi>September,</hi> 1643. at the houre aforeſaid, are poſſeſſed by the ſaid Roman Catholique Subjects now in Arms, &amp;c. or their party. And that all ſuch Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tyes, Baronyes, Lands, Tenements, and hereditaments, in the ſaid Province, which on the ſaid fifteenth of <hi>September,</hi> 1643. at the houre aforeſaid, are poſſeſſed by the ſaid Roman Catholique Subjects now in Armes, &amp;c. and their party, ſhall remaine intirely during this Ceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſation in the hands and Poſſeſſion of the ſaid Roman Catholique Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jects now in Armes &amp;c. and their party, ſaving and excepting there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out all places protected by any Commander, deriving Authority from his Majeſty, and likewiſe excepting thereout all ſuch Territories, Caſtles, Towns, Lands, Tenements, and hereditaments, which on the ſaid fifteenth day of <hi>September</hi> 1643. at the houre aforeſaid are poſſeſsed by any of his Majeſtyes Proteſtant Subjects, or ſuch as ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>haere unto them. And it is concluded and accorded, that the like rule for Corne ſowne, and what ſhall be payed for protected places; and for the laying down of waſts for the reſpective Gariſons, ſhall be ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerved in the Province of <hi>Vlſter,</hi> as is ſet downe for <hi>Leinſter.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb n="7" facs="tcp:124745:5"/>
            <p>
               <hi>Item.</hi> It is concluded and accorded, that the quarters in the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vince of <hi>Connaght,</hi> be as followeth, <hi>viz.</hi> that the County of <hi>Galway,</hi> the County of the town of <hi>Galway,</hi> the Counties of <hi>Mayo, Roſcomon, Sligo,</hi> and <hi>Letrym,</hi> in the Province of <hi>Connaght,</hi> and all ſuch caſtles, lands, tenements and hereditaments in the ſaid Province which the ſaid fifteenth day of <hi>September,</hi> 1643. at the houre aforeſaid are poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſed by the ſaid Roman Catholick ſubjects, now in armes, &amp;c, and their party, ſhall during the ſaid ceſſation remain entirely in the poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſion of the ſaid Roman Catholick ſubjects, now in arms and their party, excepting all ſuch Territories, caſtles, lands, tenements and he<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reditaments within the ſaid ſeveral Counties which upon the ſaid 15. of <hi>September</hi> 1643. at the houre aforeſaid, are poſſeſſed by any of his Majeſties Forces, or by their party, or by any of them, and that thoſe who after taking protection of any of his Majeſties Forces, or any of that party, or from any Governours, deriving Authority from his Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſty there, have joyned themſelves to the ſaid Roman Catholick ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jects now in armes, &amp;c. and their party, ſhall pay no contribution un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to ſuch who protected them. But in regard there may be a rule diffe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rent touching perſons that may be ſaid to doe this, and conſequently touching the Contributions payable by them. It is concluded and ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>corded that ſuch diſputes and queſtions, if any ſhall ariſe, be determi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned by Commiſſioners indifferently choſen on each ſide, and it is concluded and accorded, that the like rule for ſowers and manurers of corne within the quarters of each other, ſhall be obſerved in the Province of <hi>Connaght,</hi> as is ſet downe for <hi>Leinſter.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Item.</hi> It is concluded and accorded, and the ſaid Marqueſſe of <hi>Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mond;</hi> for and in the name of his Majeſty doth promiſe and under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>take, that no interruption ſhall be given unto any of the ſaid Roman Catholick ſubjects now in Armes, &amp;c. or their party, in any of the ſaid Counties, quarters, or places by the ſaid precedent Articles unto them or any of them limited as aforeſaid, during this Ceſſation; like as the ſaid <hi>Donnogh</hi> Viſcount <hi>Muskery,</hi> and the reſt of the above na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med perſons who are authorized, as aforeſaid, do promiſe and under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>take, that no interruption ſhal be given unto any of his Majeſties For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces, Proteſtant ſubjects, or ſuch as adhere unto them, within any of the ſaid Counties, qu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="4 letters">
                  <desc>••••</desc>
               </gap>rs or places, by the preced<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nt Articles limi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted unto them, as aforeſaid, during the ſaid Ceſſation.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Item.</hi> It is concluded and accorded, that no Officer of the Armie, or Souldier of eithe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> ſide, ſhall be admitted without licence from the Commander in chiefe of the Army on both ſides, or of the Comman<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der of the next chiefe Garriſons reſpectively to paſſe or repaire into any gariſon on either ſide, ſave that it be lawfull for either party to
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:124745:6"/>furniſh any gariſon in their power during the Ceſſation, with victu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>als, cloth, amunition or other neceſſaries by licence, as aforeſaid, which is not to be denied upon demand.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Item.</hi> It is concluded and accorded, that if any Army or Forces in this Kingdom raiſed by his Majeſties authority, or any part there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, or any other his Majeſties ſubjects ſhall not yeeld obedience to the Articles of this Ceſſation, but ſhal publickly ſtand in oppoſition there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>unto; that the ſaid Roman Catholick ſubjects now in Armes, &amp;c. and their party may perſecute ſuch: and the ſaid <hi>Iames</hi> Marqueſſe of <hi>Ormonde</hi> doth promiſe and undertake that ſuch who ſhall ſo ſtand in oppoſition, ſhall not be aſſiſted, protected, or defended againſt the ſaid Roman Catholick Subjects now in armes, &amp;c. or their party, by his Majeſty or any of his forces. And yet nevertheleſſe the ſame ſhall not be underſtood to be any breach of ceſſation, as to other parts of the kingdome, which ſhall conforme and yeeld thereunto. And whereas the aſſiſtance of his Majeſties forces is deſired by the ſaid Roman Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tholick ſubjects now in armes, &amp;c. againſt ſuch as ſhall oppoſe the Articles of this ceſſation and will not yeeld obedience thereunto, or interrupt the trade and traffick, albeit that it is not to be ſuppoſed that there will be any ſuch, the ſaid <hi>Iames</hi> Marqueſſe of <hi>Ormonde</hi> doth further promiſe and undertake, that their ſaid requeſt ſhall be made known to his Majeſty, and upon ſignification of his pleaſure the ſame ſhall be obeyed.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Item,</hi> It is concluded and accorded, that if in other caſes it be pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended on either ſide that the Ceſſation is violated, that yet no Act of Hoſtility is immediately to follow; but firſt the party complaining is to acquaint the Lord Generall, Lieutenant Generall, or other chiefe Commander of either ſide in that Province, in which the ſaid Ceſſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion is pretended to be violated therewith, and to allow fourteene dayes after notice given, for reparation or ſatisfaction, and in caſe re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paration or ſatisfaction be not given or tendred, then fourteen dayes notice to be given before Hoſtility begin.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Item.</hi> It is concluded and accorded, that all Priſoners and hoſtages of both ſides in all parts of the Kingdome, excepting ſuch of them as are indicted of any Capitall offence, ſhall de mutually releaſed and ſet at liberty, within ſeven dayes after publication of the ſaid Ceſſation. And the ſaid Marqueſſe of <hi>Ormonde,</hi> doth further promiſe and under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>take; that ſuch priſoners who indicted of any capitall offence, ſhall be ſet at liberty upon Baile, untill his Majeſties further pleaſure be knowne therein. Provided nevertheleſſe that if any party of his Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſties Army in any other Province of the Kingdom, ſhall not with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in ten dayes after publication of theſe Articles, yeeld obedience
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:124745:6"/>thereunto; that the ſame ſhall be no breach of ceſſation, but that his Majeſty be firſt made acquainted with ſuch diſobedience, &amp; his di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rection expected therein: &amp; that all other perſons that do reſide with either party, and all women and children ſhall be permitted within ſeven dayes after publiſhing of this ceſſation, or when they pleaſe, with their goods and chattels, to depart to what place they pleaſe, with a ſafe conduct or convoy if they deſire it.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Item.</hi> It is concluded and accorded, that the ſaid Roman Catho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick Subjects, now in armes, &amp;c. and their party, may at any time du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring the ceſſation ſend ſuch Agents to his Majeſty as they ſhall think fit: and that the ſaid Agents ſhall have ſafe conduct in writing from the chiefe Governour or Governours of this Kingdome for the time being, upon demand.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Item.</hi> It is concluded and accorded, and the ſaid Marqueſſe of <hi>Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mond,</hi> doth promiſe and undertake for and in the name of his Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſty, that all and every of the precedent Articles, which have bin agreed unto, and undertaken by the ſaid Marqueſſe, for and in the behalfe of his Majeſty, ſhall be faithfully, truly, and inviolably obſerved, fulfil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led and kept. And the ſaid Viſcount <hi>Muskery,</hi> Sir <hi>Lucas Dillon,</hi> Knight, <hi>Nicholas Plunket,</hi> 
               <abbr>Eſq</abbr> Sir <hi>Robert Talbot,</hi> Baronet, Sir <hi>Rich<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ard Barnewell, Torlogh ô Oncale, Evea Mach Gennis, Geffry Browne,</hi> and <hi>Iohn Walſh,</hi> 
               <abbr>Eſq</abbr> For and in the behalfe of the ſaid Roman Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tholick ſubjects, now in armes, &amp;c. and their party do promiſe and undertake, that all and every of the precedent Articles, which have agreed unto and undertaken by them, for and in the behalfe of their party, ſhall be faithfull, truly, &amp; inviolably obſerved, fulfilled, &amp; kept.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Laſtly.</hi> It is concluded and accorded, that all poſſeſſions, and like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe all goods and chattels, that ſhall be found <hi>in Specie,</hi> taken by either party, after the houre of twelve aforeſaid, and before publica<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of this Ceſſation, ſhall be reſtored to the owners, and after pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lication, all poſſeſſion and goods that ſhall be taken, to be reſtored to the owners upon demand, or dammages for the ſame.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>In witneſſe</hi> whereof the ſaid Marqueſſe to the party of the ſaid Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticles remaining with the ſaid Viſcount <hi>Muskery</hi> and the reſt of the above named perſons, hath put his hand and Seale. And the ſaid Viſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>count <hi>Muskery,</hi> Sir <hi>Lucas Dillon,</hi> Knight, <hi>Nicholas Plunket,</hi> 
               <abbr>Eſq</abbr> Sir <hi>Robert Talbat,</hi> Baronet, Sir <hi>Richard Barnewell,</hi> Baronet, <hi>Torlogh ô Neale, Geffry Browne, ever Mac-Gennis,</hi> and <hi>Iohn Walſh,</hi> Eſquires. To that part of the Articles remaining with the ſaid Marqueſſe <hi>Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monde,</hi> have put their hands and ſeales, the day and yeare, firſt above written.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>Muskry. Lucas Dillon. Nic. Plunket. Rob. Talbot. Rich. Barnewell. Torl. ô Neale. Geffry Browne. Ever Magennis. Io. Walſh.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="10" facs="tcp:124745:7"/>
            <head>An Inſtrument touching the manner of payment of 30800 pound ſterling, by ſeverall payments.</head>
            <p>VVHereas by an Inſtrument bearing date with theſe pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſents, we have in the behalfe, and by authority from the Roman Catholicks of this Kingdome, freely given unto his Majeſty the ſum of thirty thouſand pounds ſterling, wherein the times or manner of payments are not expreſſed. We do therefore hereby agree, that the ſame ſhall be paid in manner follow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, <hi>viz.</hi> 5000 pounds within one moneth next after the date of theſe preſents, the one halfe in money, and the other halfe in good and Merchantable Beeves, not under four, or above ten yeares old, at the rate of 30 pounds the ſcore, at the City of <hi>Dublin,</hi> 5000 pounds more: within one moneth, next after the ſaid firſt moneth; the one halfe in money, and the other halfe in Beeves as aforeſaid, at the like rates at the City of <hi>Dublin</hi> aforeſaid; alſo within two moneths next after, five thouſand pounds more, whereof one halfe in Beeves, as aforeſaid, at the like rates; and the other halfe in money: one other five thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand pounds, at or before the laſt of February next, and the ſumme of 10000 pounds, being the laſt payment of the ſaid thirty thouſand pounds, at or before the laſt day of May next, which ſhall be in the year 1644. And we hereby further agree, that eight hundred pounds more ſhall be paid to his Majeſties uſe, to whom the Lords Juſtices ſhall appoint at the Garriſon of <hi>Naas,</hi> within two moneths next in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuing, the one halfe by one moneths end next after the date hereof, and the other halfe by the end of one moneth more, next after that firſt moneth; all other payments in money, ſave the eight hundred pounds ſhall be paid at <hi>Dublin,</hi> and the reſt of the Beeves, ſave the ſaid firſt two payments, to be paid within the ſeverall Provinces to His Majeſties uſe, to ſuch perſons as ſhall be appointed by his Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſties Lords Juſtices, or other chiefe Governour or Governours in this Kingdome; they firſt giving notice to us, or any one or more of us, of their pleaſures therein. <hi>In witneſſe</hi> whereof, we have hereunto put our hands and Seales the ſixteenth day of September. 1643.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>Muskery. Lucas Dillon. Nic. Plunket, Rob. Talbot. R. Barnewell. Ter. Neale. Geffry Browne. Ever Magennis. Io. Walſh.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
